{
  "1": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Who Created Google ?",
      "options": [
        "Larry Page & Sergy Brin",
        "Mark Zuckerberg & Taylor Elliot",
        "Steve Jobs & Michael Dorovich",
        "Michelle Vine & Stuart Little"
      ],
      "answer": "1419a2d0780b20307b4b6fd0bc520159"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which Element Is Common In All Acids ?",
      "options": [
        "Oxygen",
        "Magnesium",
        "Hydrogen",
        "Calcium"
      ],
      "answer": "e4ce2ac56db8b92aa60065aee6884c25"
    }
  },
  "2": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of India during the Kargil War of 1999 ?",
      "options": [
        "Manmohan Singh",
        "Adal Bihari Vajpayee",
        "Indira Gandhi",
        "Morarji Desai"
      ],
      "answer": "31c7714bb9d760cd1e199baa61622e6a"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Who was the women that won the Nobel Peace Prize of 2014 ?",
      "options": [
        "Indira Gandhi",
        "Prathiba Patil",
        "Marie Curie",
        "Malala"
      ],
      "answer": "2a5c29ad0725db64cb720dc1217da2f7"
    }
  },
  "3": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Who Was The Leader Who Introduced Five Year Plans ?",
      "options": [
        "Joseph Stalin",
        "Vladimir Ilyich Ulyanov",
        "John Maynard Keynes",
        "George W. Bush"
      ],
      "answer": "4ae616eb7c9196e2cf8c78efea13f64c"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Who Was The First Person To Win Nobel Prize In Both Physics And Chemistry ?",
      "options": [
        "Pierre Curie",
        "Marie Curie",
        "Irène Joliot‑Curie",
        "Albert Einstein"
      ],
      "answer": "8ee140eab9e0fc6fc162ba80793e9b06"
    }
  },
  "4": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Who Founded International Red Cross and Red Crescent Movement ?",
      "options": [
        "Adan Dilday, Rayford Vanderford",
        "Henry Dunant, Gustave Moynier",
        "Moises Laferriere, Timmy Jeppson",
        "Adrien Barrientez, Sean Harvard"
      ],
      "answer": "f6fd70438c2c2337c059dbb0b21da1e5"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which Scientist Among The Following Has A Chemical Element Named After Him ?",
      "options": [
        "Issac Newton",
        "Albert Einstein",
        "Alexander Graham Bell",
        "Satyendra Nath Bose"
      ],
      "answer": "7560afa1f46d5e5fefe4ad93e42a293d"
    }
  },
  "5": {
    "0": {
      "question": "'Mein Kampf' Is The Autobiography of Whom ?",
      "options": [
        "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Helen Keller",
        "Benito Mussolini",
        "Adolf Hitler"
      ],
      "answer": "540dea05a35b0fc9a050f36db954a484"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Whose Autobiogrpahy's Title Is 'The Story Of My Experiements With Truth' ?",
      "options": [
        "Helen Keller",
        "Martin Luther King",
        "Mahatma Gandhi",
        "Nelson Mandela"
      ],
      "answer": "17f43afc21a80eeda781fee0b64aace7"
    }
  },
  "6": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Which Was The Paramilitary Wing Of Nazi Party ?",
      "options": [
        "Brownshirts",
        "Blackshirts",
        "Redshirts",
        "Darkshirts"
      ],
      "answer": "561c4f8d3e2bcac35469cf076118a5e0"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which Was The Paramilitary Wing Of Fascist Party ?",
      "options": [
        "Brownshirts",
        "Blackshirts",
        "Redshirts",
        "Darkshirts"
      ],
      "answer": "408a0e3d567d753dac2bfb17d4c6f7ef"
    }
  },
  "7": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Which Of The Following Gases Is Used In Fluorescent Lamps ?",
      "options": [
        "Mercury",
        "Oxygen",
        "Hydrogen",
        "Chlorine"
      ],
      "answer": "34dae487e31f37aa74633258b7774d4f"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which Is The Chemical Element With The Least Electronegativity ?",
      "options": [
        "Fulorine",
        "Curium",
        "Einsteinium",
        "Francium"
      ],
      "answer": "8a85b22d3e098dfba96b12c0b044239a"
    }
  },
  "8": {
    "0": {
      "question": "What Does HTTP Stands For In Terms Of Internet ?",
      "options": [
        "Hyper Text Tele Protocol",
        "High Tele Transfer Protocol",
        "Hyper Text Transfer Protocol",
        "Hyper Traversing Transfer Protocol"
      ],
      "answer": "aad79b04a086589c5d1f24b822b340d8"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which Canal Links Mediterranean Sea And Red Sea ?",
      "options": [
        "Suez Canal",
        "Panama Canal",
        "Manchester Canal",
        "Grand Canal"
      ],
      "answer": "3803cb4ab3ac5ac8ce9fb441767d592e"
    }
  },
  "9": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Which two months in a year have the same calendar ? ",
      "options": [
        "June, October ",
        "October, December ",
        "June, July",
        "April, July"
      ],
      "answer": "d8656973dbb65cf225e66c609fec43dc"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Who Introduced The New Deal Policy During The Great Depression ?",
      "options": [
        "Joseph Stalin",
        "Franklin Roosevelt",
        "Theodore Roosevelt",
        "Winston Churchill"
      ],
      "answer": "a87b2ffeb02d87630898992cbc88aa48"
    }
  },
  "10": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Who Wrote The Book 'War & Peace' ?",
      "options": [
        "Karl Marx",
        "Leo Tolstoy",
        "William Shakespeare",
        "Agatha Christie"
      ],
      "answer": "4bd0257a6736b9a1066d6ee32ae9218b"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Athos & Porthos Are Among The Three Muskteers, Who Is Third One ?",
      "options": [
        "D'Artagnan",
        "Rochefort",
        "Planchet",
        "Aramis"
      ],
      "answer": "d6b3462a8b22d946ee0913c00a247145"
    }
  },
  "11": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Where Did Vasco Da Gama Die ?",
      "options": [
        "Portugal",
        "India",
        "Spain",
        "South Africa"
      ],
      "answer": "7d31e0da1ab99fe8b08a22118e2f402b"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which Chemical Is Used To Artificially Ripen Fruits ?",
      "options": [
        "Ethylene",
        "Carbon Di Oxide",
        "Methane",
        "Neon"
      ],
      "answer": "18f71a980170960aca68f74ec702c5be"
    }
  },
  "12": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Who Developed The First Vaccine ?",
      "options": [
        "Louis Pasteur",
        "Harvi",
        "Ronald Ross",
        "Edward Jenner"
      ],
      "answer": "4d954b7bb05e3f07e9a16eb6b05a47b3"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which Disease Is Caused Due To Deficiency Of Vitamin-B1 ?",
      "options": [
        "Ricket",
        "Scurvy",
        "Beriberi",
        "Goitre"
      ],
      "answer": "d97d6fc0904d1b7b82411962d8c48ac3"
    }
  },
  "13": {
    "0": {
      "question": "What Is The Name Of The Lowest Part Of Atmosphere ?",
      "options": [
        "Stratosphere",
        "Troposphere",
        "Exosphere",
        "Mesosphere"
      ],
      "answer": "1b4f1cbc72838eb58299591c20f3a872"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Who Is The First Women Prime Minister In The World ?",
      "options": [
        "Indira Gandhi",
        "Margaret Thatcher",
        "Sirimavo Bandaranaike",
        "Hilary Clinton"
      ],
      "answer": "1283f060a5a067cba97cb22a0116371e"
    }
  },
  "14": {
    "0": {
      "question": "Which Country Is Not A Permanent Member in United Nations' Security Council ?",
      "options": [
        "France",
        "China",
        "Japan",
        "Russia"
      ],
      "answer": "53a577bb3bc587b0c28ab808390f1c9b"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "Which planet is named after the Roman god of war?",
      "options": [
        "Neptune",
        "Mars",
        "Mercury",
        "Venus"
      ],
      "answer": "671f028142280b556a85ffdd90e0a43d"
    }
  },
  "15": {
    "0": {
      "question": "When Did The Russian Revolution Occur According To Gregorian Calendar (Provisional Government) ?",
      "options": [
        "March 1917",
        "February 1917",
        "March 1918",
        "February 1918"
      ],
      "answer": "116e0d810a9b7052863fd14dcf03b0a9"
    },
    "1": {
      "question": "When Did United Nations Came Into Existence ?",
      "options": [
        "1948",
        "1946",
        "1945",
        "1947"
      ],
      "answer": "2d00f43f07911355d4151f13925ff292"
    }
  }
}
